A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Occasional Papers FA949
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Occasional Papers
1958-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University Press
FA949
1.32 Cubic Feet 2 boxes and 1 package (18 volumes).
2 boxes and 1 package (18 volumes).
Arrangement
Arranged numerically by volume number 1-18.
Essentially chronological.
Scope and Contents
Occasional papers by the faculty and friends of The Rockefeller Institute/University. Rockefeller University Press, N.Y. no. 1 (1958) and later numbers.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Biographical / Historical
Title changed: no. 8, Occasional papers of The Rockefeller Institute; no. 14, Occasional papers of The Rockefeller University. Addresses or tributes presented or delivered on various occasions and published by The Rockefeller University Press.& See card catalog under Occasional papers for fuller description of each item.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 541
Cell and biomolecular sciences; Science -- Study and teaching; Life sciences; Biology -- Research; Medical research; Medicine, Preventive; Medical sciences; Medical technology; Medical education; Rockefeller University Press
- Weiss, Paul A. The message of science, 1958; 1 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Presented at the Universal and International Exposition at Brussels.
- Bronk, Detlev W. Address of welcome, 12th General Assembly of the International Scientific Radio Union, 1957; 2 (Box 1)
- Corner, George W. The Johns Hopkins University and The Rockefeller Institute: allies in the march of science, 1959; 3 (Box 1)
- Bronk, Detlev W. Presentation of the George M. Kober medal to Herbert S. Gasser, 1954; 4 (Box 1)
- Dubos, René. Medical Utopias, 1959; 5 (Box 1)
- Bronk, Detlev W. On the economic and social contributions of life insurance to the nation: the viewpoint of the scientist, 1959; 6 (Box 1)
- Shope, Richard E. Comparative medicine, 1959; 7 (Box 1)
- Convocation for the conferring of degrees, 1959; 8 (Box 1)
- Convocation for the conferring of degrees, 1960; 9 (Box 1)
- Kac, Mark. Mathematics: its trends and its tensions, 1961; 10 (Box 1)
- Lord Adrian. Francis Bacon, the advocate of science, 1961; 11 (Box 1)
- Convocation for the conferring of degrees, 1961; 12 (Box 1)
- Smith, John E. Philosophy in America Today, 1961; 13 (Box 1)
- Barklie McKee Henry, 1902-1966, 14 (Box 1)
- Reminiscences of Anthony J. Campo, 1970; 15 (Box 1)
- A notable career in finding out: Peyton Rous, 1879-1970, 16 (Box 1)
  Published in 1971 in a limited edition of 1500 copies bound in hardcover for family and friends.
- A notable career in finding out: Peyton Rous, 1879-1970. Published in 1971 in pamphlet form, 16 bis; package. 16 bis (Package 1)
- Dubos, René. The human environment in technological societies, 1968 July-August; unumbered; package (Package 1)
  Reprinted from The Rockefeller University Review
- Baker, William O. Remarks on the occasion of the twenty-fifth anniversary of David Rockefeller as chairman of the Board of Trustees, The Rockefeller University. RU Press, 1975, 1950-1975; 16 bis; 8 pp., 16 bis (Box 2)
  Cover title: David Rockefeller; the first quarter-century 1950-1975
- Recollections of Detlev W. Bronk, 1897-1975. By colleagues and friends at a gathering in Caspary Auditorium on February 18, 1976. New York, New York, The Rockefeller University Press, 1976, 17; 46 pp. (Box 2)
  Cover title: 1897-1975.
  (Occasional paper, 17).
- Lederberg, Joshua, Presidential address at his installation as President of The Rockefeller University. New York, The Rockefeller University Press, 1979; 18; 8 pp. (Box 2)
  (Occasional paper, 18). Delivered October 16, 1978.